Varun

01A, Aspire Point, 210 High Street London E15 2ZL, United Kingdom

varun.or.varun@gmail.com

+44 7824774906

Right after my graduation I joined a multinational company and have been working there for the past 5 years. I have skills and attributes such as leadership, analytical thinking, problem solving, team working and communication. I am currently pursuing a Masters programme in Artificial Intelligence, which would help me understand the technology in depth and turn my innovative ideas into reality.

Education

2012 - 2016

Bachelor of Engineering, Electrical and Electronics Government Engineering College, Barton Hill

Core modules: Object Oriented Programming, Advanced, Control Theory, Solid State Devices, Power Electronics, Control System, Microprocessors and Applications, Digital signal processing.

Projects: Worked on an IOT project that will collect the pollution data from cars and display it dynamically via cloud. Create a quadcopter from scratch. Create a robot which can follow a line.

Techstack: Raspberry pi, HTML, Javascript, node, AWS server

2021 - Present

Master of Science, Artificial Intelligence
Queen Mary University of London

Core modules: Al in games, NLP, Neural Network, Computer Vision, Computational Creativity, Information Retrieval.

Projects: Create an AI agent for Atari games, Sentiment Analysis of IMDb reviews. Conditional Random Field Sequence tagger. Vector space semantics for similarity between characters in a series. Image generation from description using GANs. Language models using Neural networks. Create a search engine from scratch. Super resolution using deep neural networks.

Techstack: Python, Java, Javascript, HTML

Work Experience

2016 - 2021

QBurst Technologies Pvt. Ltd
Post: Senior Software Engineer
Country: India and Japan

- Incharge of architecting, developing and deploying an E-Commerce application for Uniqlo, a Japanese Clothing Company from scratch.

- Had the opportunity to live in Tokyo and work with the clients, which helped me in developing the skills of effective communication, versatility, individual ownership and time management.
- Proficiency in programming languages such as C, Javascript, Python, SQL etc
- Was responsible for mentoring and assigning tasks to junior developers.
- Create REST APIs for integration with frontend.

Techstack: Typescript, React, Node, Golang, SSR, Docker, AWS, Firebase, Jenkins

2021 - Present QBurst Technologies Pvt. Ltd

Post: Software Development Consultant

Country: United Kingdom

- Coordinated with development teams to analyse problems and find efficient solutions for them.
- Requirement analysis and design architecture.
- Implemented server side rendering for the react application.
- Making the application responsive and efficient.
- Overall application optimisation.
- Use lerna to create mono-repo with nexus integration.
- Use microservice architecture for more flexibility
- Design and implement caching layers for efficiency.

Techstack: Typescript, React, SSR, AWS, Firebase, Akamai

Skills

- Exceptional communication and networking skills.
- Ability to follow instructions and deliver quality results on time.
- Ability to work under pressure and multi-task.

Courses

- Currently undertaking a training and certification program in machine learning provided by Amazon.
- Rakuten technology conference, Tokyo.
- Have participated in many technical conferences organized by Google in Tokyo.

Languages

- English: Read, write and speak fluently.
- Hindi: Read, write and speak fluently.
- Malayalam and few more regional languages: speak fluently.

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/varun-0b14a1169/

Github: https://github.com/varuns-github, https://github.com/varunsanthosh

Profile and projects: https://varuns-github.github.io/